Many people just love to pair wine and chocolate, and I do too, they're two of my best friends and a match made in heaven.
But wine and chocolate is a very complicated match up.
Here's why.
Chocolate has just about everything going for it.
It's very high in fat which is mouth coating and makes the wine taste a little thinner.
Chocolate can also have a little bit of bitterness in it, which is something we have to be careful with.
Chocolate has lots and lots of sugar which can also make a wine pairing kind of tough.
And chocolate is the most intense flavor on the face of the earth, in my opinion.
That can make it a little bit difficult for a wine to match up with chocolate.
So what we need to do is find a wine that can stand up to the sweetness, stand up to the flavor, not have any bitterness, and not manage the onslaught of all that fat from chocolate.
If we can find that wine, it's just perfect.
There's a lot of different types of chocolate out there, and each of them have their own method of pairing up with wine.
But let's say for chocolate, the perfect match is a rich, sweet, red wine that can match on the taste, and the flavor, and the texture.
In my opinion the best wine in the world for chocolate would be a nice ruby port, perhaps a late harvest Zinfandel, or even a sparkling Shiraz from Australia.
Try any of those wines with chocolate and you'll have a great match.